nationallgbtmuseum.org 2014-02-10

# Privacy Policy

The Velvet Foundation (together with its affiliates, successors, and assigns) (“we/us”), care about your privacy and recognize the importance of protecting personal information when you visit velvetfoundation.org and all subdomains (the “Site”). Our Privacy Policy is designed to assist you in understanding how we collect, use, and safeguard the personal information you provide to us, and to assist you in making informed decisions when using the Site. The servers that make the Site available, and databases where information may be stored, may be located outside the country from which you accessed the Site, but we will collect, process, and use personal information only in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

  **1\. What Information Is Collected?**

We collect personal information (sometimes referred to as “personally identifiable information”) from our online visitors on a voluntary basis and only in order to create or enhance our relationship with you. This includes, for example, keeping you updated with developments in our mission, requesting volunteer assistance, and soliciting donations. The personal information we ask for is usually your first and last name, e-mail address, phone number, and mailing address. If you make a donation to the Velvet Foundation through the Site, we may collect information necessary to effect the donation, including, without limitation, your address, credit card number, security code, and expiration date. 

 **2\. How Is the Information Collected?  **

 ****We collect personally identifiable information via conventional Internet forms. In addition, certain sections of the Site may use “cookies.” Cookies are very small data files left on your computer by the Site. These files can then be accessed by the Site in the future. Most browsers are automatically set to accept cookies. Most browsers will allow you to erase cookies from your computer hard drive, block acceptance of cookies, or receive a warning before a cookie is stored. You should refer to your browser instructions or “Help” screen to learn more about how to manage cookies. Please note, however, that if you block cookies, some portions of the Site may not function properly.

Like most standard websites, we use log files. This includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the Site, track users’ movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses and similar data are not linked to personally identifiable information.

Some of the Sites and Services may contain electronic images called web beacons, sometimes known as one pixel GIFs, clear GIFs, or pixel tags, which allow us to count visitors who have viewed the Site. When we send promotional e-mail messages and newsletters, for example, web beacons allow us to count how many subscribers have read them. Web beacons allow us to develop statistical information about the activities and features that most interest our users for the purpose of providing more personalized content. By setting your browser to display HTML e-mails as text only, you might be able to prevent the use of some web beacons. Please consult the “Help” section of your browser for more information. 

 **3\. Information Usage and Distribution  **

 ****As stated above, we collect personally identifiable information to create or enhance our relationship with you, including, without limitation, to e-mail you with updates, requests for volunteer assistance, and solicitations of donations. Only those who provide us their e-mail addresses will receive follow-up e-mail or other communications from us. We also offer visitors an “opt-out” option at any time they wish to cease receiving e-mails or other information from us (see Section 8 below). We may share information with other trusted third parties who work on behalf of or with the Velvet Foundation under confidentiality agreements.  

 **3\. Legal Disclaimer  **

 ****Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process (including, without limitation, a subpoena) served on the Site or its owner.  

 **4\. Aggregate Information (Non-Personally Identifiable)  **

 ****We may share aggregated demographic information with third parties. This is not linked to any personally identifiable information.  

 **5\. Business Transactions  **

 ****In the event that the Velvet Foundation or the Site is/are sold or transferred, or in the event that substantially all of the Velvet Foundation’s assets are sold or transferred to a third party, the Site and any personally identifiable information collected by us will be among the transferred assets. By using the Site, you hereby agree to such transfer or assignment of your personal information collected by the Velvet Foundation, and you further waive any claims that could be made against us in relation thereto.  

 **6\. Links to Third-Party Sites  **

 ****The Sites may from time to time contain links to third-party websites. You should always check the privacy policy of any linked website to understand its personal information collection practices, including how it may use cookies. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites. If you are concerned about the privacy policy of a certain third party, you may contact it directly or visit the individual website to learn more about its individual privacy policies.  

 **7\. Data Security  **

 ****We use reasonable administrative, technical, personnel, and physical measures to safeguard your personal information in our possession against loss, theft, and unauthorized use, disclosure, or modification. In addition, we also use reasonable methods to make sure that your personal information is accurate, up-to-date, and appropriately complete.  

 **8\. Opt-Out/Removal of Personal Information  **

 ****If you do not want us to send you e-mail, offline communications or other information, you can request removal of your information at any time, by contacting us by e-mail at[info@velvetfoundation.org](mailto:info@velvetfoundation.org) or by mailing a request to: Attn: Privacy Policy, Velvet Foundation, 529 14th Street, NW, #545, Washington, DC 20045. 

 **9\. Questions or Complaints  **

 ****If you have any questions, complaints, or comments regarding our Privacy Policy, please contact The Velvet Foundation by email at[info@velvetfoundation.org](mailto:info@velvetfoundation.org) or by writing to: Attn: Privacy Policy, Velvet Foundation, 529 14th Street, NW, #545, Washington, DC 20045. 

 **10\. If You Refuse to Provide Information Online  **

 ****The Velvet Foundation does not require registration or submission of personally identifiable information to obtain basic access to the Site. We do not require the submission of personally identifiable information for a user to contribute content to the Site. However, we reserve the right to limit access to areas and functions of the Site to users who have submitted such information.  

 **11\. Children’s Privacy  **

 ****Children under the age of 13 are not permitted to use the Site. **IF YOU ARE UNDER 13 YEARS OF AGE, DO NOT USE OR ACCESS THE SITE AT ANY TIME OR IN ANY MANNER.** The Velvet Foundation does not knowingly collect any information from anyone under the age of 13. If you are the parent or legal guardian of a child under 13 who you believe has submitted information to the Site, please contact us immediately at [scofieldt@velvetfoundation.org](mailto:scofieldt@velvetfoundation.org). 

 **12\. Your California Privacy Rights  **

 ****California Civil Code § 1798.83 permits users who are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an e-mail to info@velvetfoundation.org or write us at:

Attn: CA Privacy  
Velvet Foundation  
529 14th Street, NW #545  
Washington, DC 20045 

 **13\. General Terms and Conditions of Use/Notice of Changes  **

 ****The terms of this Privacy Policy are incorporated by reference in our general Terms of Service. Please review our Terms of Use [insert link]. By using the Site, you signify your assent to this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, you are not authorized to use the Site. We reserve the right to make changes in this Privacy Policy, provided that we give notice to you of any such changes via e-mail and/or by posting the amended Privacy Policy on the Site. Please check back from time to time to ensure you are aware of any such notices of changes in our privacy practices. Your continued use of the Site will signify your acceptance of these changes.
